Kunal Mehra

🗣 Gurugram, Harayana 🛘 🗷 kunalmehra 240304@gmail.com 🕓 +91 93290 37858 in LinkedIn 垜 Github 🌐 kunalmehra 075. github.io

As a **Full Stack Web Developer** with nearly **2 years** of experience in the **MERN** stack, I am dedicated to writing production-ready code that is both effective and unique. Valuing **skills** over formal degrees, I aim to bring innovative solutions to the IT world. I am seeking opportunities to contribute to a team where I can drive success for both myself and the organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript | TypeScript | React | React Native | Node.is | Express | REST APIs | MongoDB | MySQL | Redis
- Redux Toolkit | Webpack | Unit Testing (Jest, Vitest) | Integration Testing | Selenium Automation | Sonarqube | Playwright
- Chakra/Material UI | Bootstrap | Shadon | Tailwind CSS | CSS Preprocessors | SaaS | Figma | Storybook
- Firebase | Cloud Firestore | AWS | GCP | Google Auth | Google Analytics | Serverless | Jenkins | Docker
- WebSockets (Socket.io) | Payment Gateways (PhonePe, CC Avenue, Razorpay)

EXPERIENCE -----

86 Agency (Software Engineer)

Gurugram, IND June 2023- Present

- Developed **over 20+ web applications** using **React**, **Node**, and **MongoDB**, leveraging multiple UI libraries and many different technologies to handle complex **CRUD** operations with appropriate code **quality** and **readability**.
- Collaborated with international clients, creating APIs, resolving complex issues in their codebases, and integrating Apple and Google Passes into mobile wallets with notification management.
- Created a design system using Shadon and Storybook, and developed a user contracts management backend.
- Conducted comprehensive unit, integration, and automation testing for mutliple apps.
- Developed a mobile meeting app with **React Native**, featuring chat, calendar events, and **video chat** with **Websockets**.
- Managed over 15 web applications on AWS, utilizing Docker, performing health checks, addressing security and vulnerability aspects, code reviews, and implementing CI/CD pipelines with Jenkins.

Pesto Fellowship, Pesto Tech (Engineering Fellow)

San Francisco, USA (Remote) July 2023- Present

- A 10-month-long program based on the MERN stack to improve the grasp of all concepts & develop problem-solving.
- Led a team of 5 in designing and developing a comprehensive Hospital Management System.
- Collaborated with tech industry professionals to discuss and solve complex technical issues based on real-life problems.

PROJECTS & MILESTONES

Github 💭 Link 🔗

- Developed **Calendly clone**, an Events/Calendar Management web service, with live event booking and calendar display.
- Designed whole backend and APIs. Also implemented Google Auth, email notifications, workflows, and reminders.
- Built using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB, in a collaborative group of 5 members over 6 days...

Ace Legal Services

MyCal

Github C Link

- Developed an online lawyers' appointment booking system, in a collaborative group of 5 members over 6 days.
- Enabled clients to book appointments, login/signup, OTP password reset, email notifications & reminders.
- Designed and Implemented CRUD operations using React, Ant Design, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.

Orangefry.com

Github 💭 Link 🔗

- Developed a UI/UX-enhanced clone of Pepperfry.com, a furniture and home decor selling web service,
- Enabled users to buy, and provided admin functionality to manage products, users, and comments.
- Built using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB as an individual project in 6 days.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Web Development, Masai School

Bengaluru, IND August 2022 - May 2022

- Learned front-end development, **React**, **Typescript**, data structures, and algorithms, and specialized in backend development with **Node.js**, Express, server-side programming, system design, and databases.
- Gained proficiency in React, spending 1200 hours coding real-time web applications and solving 800+ DSA problems.
- Dedicated 200 hours to holistic development, focusing on teamwork, remote collaboration, and project contribution skills.

Higher Secondary Education

• St. Joseph Convent Sr. School Jabalpur, MP

Jabalpur, IND July 2020 - March 2022

ADDITIONALS

 $\textbf{Soft Skills} . \ Leadership, \ Communication \ Skills, \ Adaptability, \ Problem-Solving \ \& \ Remote \ Collaboration.$

Hobbies: Playing Guitar, Football, Events & Hackathons Languages: English, Hindi